Choral Society of Washington 070
People's Archive, MLK Library
Choral Society of Washington Collection
1884-1910
People's Archive, MLK Library
Washington Choral Society (Washington, D.C.)
070
9 Linear feet
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Biographical / Historical
The first meeting of the Choral Society of Washington was held on November 7, 1883 in the home of Mr. and Mrs. Jonathan Jay Knox. At this meeting a singing society was formed with Mr. Harry C. Sherman named conductor. There were originally 52 members of the Society and Mr. Knox was named its first President. The society was officially incorporated on May 31, 1892. It is unknown when the organization became defunct.
Custodial History
The materials in this collection were originally cataloged as part of the Cutter Collection (+VYRH C45) in the Library. They were removed from that collection and accessioned in 1998 and 1999. The original donor of these materials is unknown.
Scope and Contents
The materials included in this collection are: clippings, bulletins, correspondence, programs, tickets, financial records, meeting minutes, and printed items. The "Book of Blanks" contains an example of each item printed by the Society (programs, tickets, form letters, etc.), the number ordered, and the cost to the Society. With the exception of one folder of the earliest meeting minutes, all materials are located in bound volumes. These bound volumes have been placed in acid-free boxes
Music; Correspondence; Minutes (Records); Ephemera; Organizational Records; Performing Arts
- Series 1
  - Account Book, 1894-1899 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Book of Blanks, 1896-1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1886-1910 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Secretary Reports (in File Folder), 1884-1885 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1892-1897 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1897-1899 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1899-1901 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1902-1907 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1884-1898 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1898-1910 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins (in Envelope), 1900-1905 (Box 6, Folder 3)